# **Jared Sasser**

- Email kid\_icarus3@yahoo.com
- Cell 920-202-0146
- GitHub <a href="https://github.com/KidIcarus1337">https://github.com/KidIcarus1337</a>
- LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/jared-sasser/40/562/521">https://www.linkedin.com/pub/jared-sasser/40/562/521</a>
- Milwaukee, WI

### Intro

I am a web developer. My focus is on the front-end, but I have some experience in the back-end as well in Node.js and Python. I have taught myself over the last couple of years with the aid of several online courses and occasional help of an experienced mentor.

### **Tech Skills**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Twitter Bootstrap
- slick
- Git
- Node.is
- Express.js
- Bash/Linux
- Python
- Firebase DB

## **Work Experience**

Professional Experience - Web Developer, February 2015 - Present

### **High Altitude Science**

Web Developer, (short-term contract) February 2015 - March 2015

- Designed and developed the front-end for the Weather Balloon Flight Simulator web app
- Front-end developed with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, slick, autoNumeric
- Built as a single-page app. This involved using slick to set up a slider that separated the three portions of the simulator one for the input parameters (launch date, burst altitude, etc.), one for the starting coordinates, and one for the results.

#### \_\_

### **Personal Projects**

**Galaxy Tanks - (In development)** 

- Live demo: <a href="http://kidicarus1337.github.io/galaxy-tanks/">http://kidicarus1337.github.io/galaxy-tanks/</a>
- Repo: https://github.com/KidIcarus1337/galaxy-tanks
- A single-page app (SPA) built on the HTML5 canvas that is a space-themed version of the classic tanks game
- Front-end developed with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Fabric.js
- Utilizes a custom-built physics engine that simulates gravity and collision detection among other things

#### **Snow App Project**

- Live demo: <a href="http://snow-app-project.herokuapp.com/">http://snow-app-project.herokuapp.com/</a>
- Repo: https://github.com/KidIcarus1337/SnowProject
- Unfinished prototype web app for a project which would've allowed people to hire others to shovel their driveway
- Developed front-end with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Wrote back-end with Node.js and Express.js, including registration and login functionality
- Integrated with Firebase DB

#### **Text-game Project**

- Live demo: <a href="http://kidicarus1337.github.io/Game-Project/public">http://kidicarus1337.github.io/Game-Project/public</a>
- Repo: https://github.com/KidIcarus1337/Game-Project
- Unfinished text-based game developed in my free time for experience
- Developed front-end with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

\_\_

### J.J. Keller - Data Entry, Fall 2012 - February 2013

• Helped migrate customer information to a new server setup

### Shopko - Customer Service, Fall 2008 - Fall 2012

- Primarily worked as a cashier and store front stocker
- Occasionally did some miscellaneous work

### **Education**

### Codeacademy, 2013

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- Web Projects

## **Udacity**, 2012 - 2013

- CS101 Intro to Computer Science
- CS253 Web Development

### High School Graduate, 2006 - 2010

# References

• Technical: Caleb Madrigal • Cell: 618-334-1919

• Email: caleb.madrigal@gmail.com

• Character: Jeff Krumrei • Cell: 734-716-8977
• Email: krumreij@gmail.com
• Character: John McNeill

• Cell: 920-342-6259

• Email: john.mcneill655@gmail.com